# **MARK CLINTON**

(201) 423-3284 - marklwclinton@gmail.com - New York, NY, 10019

Energetic computing graduate with an accumulated 2 years' experience in development and support roles. Helped increase the productivity of my Application Engineer department at BetBright by creating multiple MySQL queries for my team to run business reports which led to reduced errors, improved runtime and reliable, uniformed data. Developed an ad targeting web feature for a client at YOUniversal Media which saw specific search related ads displayed to the end user. Enthusiastic team player and analytical thinker looking to learn from and contribute in a software team.

## **EXPERIENCE**

Krossover (Stack Sports )

Manhattan, New York Dec 2017 – Current

# **APPLICATION ENGINEER**

Reduced ticket turnover time for the Krossover platform by 40%. Created MySQL queries to better handle regular customer issues and business reports.

Successfully identified and escalated prominent software issues to the product manager to ensure they were addressed and resolved, Improving site performance and usability for our 100,000+ users.

# **BetBright**

# **APPLICATION SUPPORT ENGINEER**

Dublin, Ireland Mar 2017 – Nov 2017 Created complex MySQL queries to gather and format data for multiple company departments.

Automated repetitive daily tasks which led to a 20% increase in weekly

ticket completion. Improving productivity.
Fixed front-end bugs using HTML, jQuery, JavaScript and CSS while

following company commit protocols.

Helped achieve and maintain a 94% approval rating for the customer service department due to increased productivity.

# **YOUniversal Media**

# J r FULL STACK DEVELOPER

Dublin, Ireland Feb 2016 – Aug 2016 Developed and implemented an ad targeting feature for a client which helped raise their revenue by 3%.

Implemented features across our client's sites using CRUD database commands. PHP with the YII framework and jQuery, JSON, AJAX, HTML and CSS

Implemented bug fixtures on client's sites using a full LINUX environment.

# **EDUCATION**

Dundalk Institute of Technology

Louth, Ireland Nov 2016

## **BA IN COMPUTING**

Pursued a passion for technology by enrolling in a Bachelor's in Computing in Software Development.

Member of the football society.

Active in my societies fundraising efforts for charities and sports clubs. Underwent a 6-month web internship for a local software company.

## **PROJECTS**

## **SCHEDULR**

## ORGANIZATIONAL WEB APP

Schedulr is an organizational tool to help keep track of upcoming tasks. Initially the conception of Schedulr came from my final year project in college. I decided to pick it up again in my spare time and develop it into a useable product.

Version 1.1 can be found on my GitHub below.

https://github.com/MarkClinton/Schedulr

Technology: PHP 5.6, Codeigniter, AngularJs, jQuery, CSS, HTML, JavaScript and some JS Plugins.

## **ADDITIONAL SKILLS**

Good knowledge of web development. Competent in back-end technologies such as PHP using frameworks such as Codeigniter.

Working knowledge of front-end technologies such as HTML5, JavaScript, jQuery, Angular 1.6.1, Bootstraps and plugins, CSS from professional and personal experience.

High working knowledge of database design and maintenance. As well as excellent MySQL skills. I am hardworking, enthusiastic, self-motivated team player.

Always learning new skills outside of office hours. Currently learning Angular 6 for better development for my personal projects.